<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rstudio on Dr. Erin Buchanan</title>
    <link>https://doomlab.github.io/tags/rstudio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rstudio on Dr. Erin Buchanan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://doomlab.github.io/tags/rstudio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gathering Text from the Web</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/gathering-text-from-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/gathering-text-from-the-web/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone! I don&amp;rsquo;t really feel like working too hard today, so I decided to write a blog post about how my student Will and I used rvest to mine articles from several different news sources for a project. All the scripts and current ongoings of this project can be found on our OSF page - this project is also connected to the GitHub folder with the files.
First, we picked four web sources to scrape - The New York Times, NPR, Fox News, and Breitbart because of their known political associations, and specifically, we focused on their political sections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mediation Moderation Workshop</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/mediation-moderation-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/mediation-moderation-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone!
I have been super swamped with a bunch of due dates that all hit in April. For a small brag, and I like making lists:
 9 revise and resubmits (four we&amp;rsquo;ve sent back, two have been accepted!) 4 conference posters and one invited talk 1 submitted grant (fingers crossed!) 2 invited papers 2 theses that I&amp;rsquo;m chairing, 2 that I&amp;rsquo;m on the committee for Data camp!  It&amp;rsquo;s been nuts, so haven&amp;rsquo;t left the house much or done much of anything else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working With Messy Text</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/working-with-messy-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/working-with-messy-text/</guid>
      <description>Heyo! I am doing my best to procrastinate here on a blustery Tuesday afternoon. So, I decided to share some code I&amp;rsquo;ve put together that solves problems in R that I used to do in perl. HTML or C++ was probably my first real language, but I love the heck out of perl. It&amp;rsquo;s never done me wrong (unlike you PHP).
Anyways! The context of this project is that we are developing a dictionary of words to complement the work done by Jonathan Haidt and Jesse Graham - learn more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Publication - Detect Low Quality Data</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/new-publication-detect-low-quality-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/new-publication-detect-low-quality-data/</guid>
      <description>My coauthor John Scofield and I just had a publication accepted at Behavior Research Methods - you can check out the publication preprint at OSF.
We thew together a website for the paper that summarizes everything we found, as well as puts all the materials together in one place - check it out.
We create a really nice R function to help you detect low quality data, which you can find on GitHub, and I even made a video that explains all the parts to the function at YouTube.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>