<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rstudio on Dr. Erin Buchanan</title>
    <link>https://doomlab.github.io/tags/rstudio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rstudio on Dr. Erin Buchanan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://doomlab.github.io/tags/rstudio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Installing RStudio Server &#43; Updates</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/installing-rstudio-server-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/installing-rstudio-server-updates/</guid>
      <description>One of the most difficult things I try to teach my students is how to deal with error messages. Due to Hurricane Laura, I am currently re-creating several projects including formr, RStudio, and a website. I thought I would detail that here.
You can find my first post on formr here: https://www.aggieerin.com/post/formr-installation-instructions/
Good news! It’s mostly the same and pretty smooth. However, I sometimes get this nonsense: installation of package ‘psych’ had non-zero exit status - any time you get the non-zero exit status message, it requires a careful look at the installation messages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Translations with rvest and Selenium</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/getting-translations-with-rvest-and-selenium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/getting-translations-with-rvest-and-selenium/</guid>
      <description>In this guide, I’ll go over how you can use web scraping rvest and Selenium to get translations from Google Translate. Note: I encourage responsible scraping - I always try to do it with some space between requests. You can only do 5000 characters at a time with the free Google translate. I will say that I tried to do this with just rvest and the predictability of the links for Google translate - but I could not get rvest to pull the right data off the page, so here’s a slightly more difficult approach that appears to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multilevel Modeling Workshop Materials</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/multilevel-modeling-workshop-materials/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/multilevel-modeling-workshop-materials/</guid>
      <description>Many thanks to Rutgers University Spanish and Portuguese Department (https://span-port.rutgers.edu/) for asking me to come talk about multilevel models. I enjoyed talking to the group, meeting Twitter friends in real life!, and I am especially impressed by what their department is doing in what is often considered a qualitative science.
I used RStudio&amp;rsquo;s Cloud to share a workspace with all the materials, packages, and other information you might need. I built the slide show using markdown, so that people could watch the slides and/or take their own notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating Your CV with Packages</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/updating-your-cv-with-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/updating-your-cv-with-packages/</guid>
      <description>Hi guys! I have finally done it! I updated my CV with Rmarkdown using Steve’s Markdown Templates. I was tempted to use the new vitae package, but I had already gone down this path before that came out, just finally getting back to it.
Link to the entire CV folder for you to use/view do stuff with: CV. Please ignore the html files in that folder, it does “knit” automatically as part of the website build using markdown - you should be using PDF and LaTex for the CV part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gathering Text from the Web</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/gathering-text-from-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/gathering-text-from-the-web/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone! I don&amp;rsquo;t really feel like working too hard today, so I decided to write a blog post about how my student Will and I used rvest to mine articles from several different news sources for a project. All the scripts and current ongoings of this project can be found on our OSF page - this project is also connected to the GitHub folder with the files.
First, we picked four web sources to scrape - The New York Times, NPR, Fox News, and Breitbart because of their known political associations, and specifically, we focused on their political sections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mediation Moderation Workshop</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/mediation-moderation-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/mediation-moderation-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone!
I have been super swamped with a bunch of due dates that all hit in April. For a small brag, and I like making lists:
 9 revise and resubmits (four we&amp;rsquo;ve sent back, two have been accepted!) 4 conference posters and one invited talk 1 submitted grant (fingers crossed!) 2 invited papers 2 theses that I&amp;rsquo;m chairing, 2 that I&amp;rsquo;m on the committee for Data camp!  It&amp;rsquo;s been nuts, so haven&amp;rsquo;t left the house much or done much of anything else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working With Messy Text</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/working-with-messy-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/working-with-messy-text/</guid>
      <description>Heyo! I am doing my best to procrastinate here on a blustery Tuesday afternoon. So, I decided to share some code I&amp;rsquo;ve put together that solves problems in R that I used to do in perl. HTML or C++ was probably my first real language, but I love the heck out of perl. It&amp;rsquo;s never done me wrong (unlike you PHP).
Anyways! The context of this project is that we are developing a dictionary of words to complement the work done by Jonathan Haidt and Jesse Graham - learn more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Publication - Detect Low Quality Data</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/new-publication-detect-low-quality-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/new-publication-detect-low-quality-data/</guid>
      <description>My coauthor John Scofield and I just had a publication accepted at Behavior Research Methods - you can check out the publication preprint at OSF.
We thew together a website for the paper that summarizes everything we found, as well as puts all the materials together in one place - check it out.
We create a really nice R function to help you detect low quality data, which you can find on GitHub, and I even made a video that explains all the parts to the function at YouTube.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
