<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dr. Erin Buchanan</title>
    <link>https://doomlab.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dr. Erin Buchanan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://doomlab.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Working With Messy Text</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/working-with-messy-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/working-with-messy-text/</guid>
      <description>Heyo! I am doing my best to procrastinate here on a blustery Tuesday afternoon. So, I decided to share some code I&amp;rsquo;ve put together that solves problems in R that I used to do in perl. HTML or C++ was probably my first real language, but I love the heck out of perl. It&amp;rsquo;s never done me wrong (unlike you PHP).
Anyways! The context of this project is that we are developing a dictionary of words to complement the work done by Jonathan Haidt and Jesse Graham - learn more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Publications</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/new-publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/new-publications/</guid>
      <description>Just wanted to do a quick post to say that the Nature Human Behavior response paper, Justify Your Alpha is now online at NHB&amp;rsquo;s website: Springer - it is free to view but not download. You can download the PDF version on OSF.
We&amp;rsquo;ve submitted a couple new papers as well - updated those on my research publications page. I also have a couple more to get done - hoping to feature some of the cool coding work I&amp;rsquo;ve done this week after taking a breather from a seriously packed week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Publication - Detect Low Quality Data</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/new-publication-detect-low-quality-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/new-publication-detect-low-quality-data/</guid>
      <description>My coauthor John Scofield and I just had a publication accepted at Behavior Research Methods - you can check out the publication preprint at OSF.
We thew together a website for the paper that summarizes everything we found, as well as puts all the materials together in one place - check it out.
We create a really nice R function to help you detect low quality data, which you can find on GitHub, and I even made a video that explains all the parts to the function at YouTube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citations in R Markdown &#43; Papaja</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/citations-in-r-markdown-papaja/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/citations-in-r-markdown-papaja/</guid>
      <description>Heyo! I wanted to write a post about some of the quirky things I&amp;rsquo;ve found with writing manuscripts in R Markdown, as well as provide a solution to a problem that someone else might be having.
Update: The csl file I describe below is a special formatted one, which was shared with me. You can download it from GitHub to try the suggestions below.
Update 2: Turns out, potentially, the suggestions from the manual are not working correctly, as Frederik has checked it out and opened an issue on github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Shiny App to Compare Stats</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/a-shiny-app-to-compare-stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/a-shiny-app-to-compare-stats/</guid>
      <description>For a recent publication comparing null hypothesis testing p-values to Bayes Factors and Observation Oriented Modeling, we created a Shiny app to graph all of our complex plots. I particularly pleased with the plotly 3D graph - as I usually think that 3D graphs are impossible to read. This plot shows what we found in our study (albeit I would recommend viewing the 2D plots more):
 Bayes Factors and p-values follow a power function, as we expected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn About MOTE</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/learn-about-mote/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/learn-about-mote/</guid>
      <description>The APA Task Force on Statistical Inference (Wilkinson &amp;amp; TFSI, 1999) has advocated the inclusion of effect sizes in journal articles as an important source of information. The fifth and current edition of the APA publication manual (2001, 2010) emphasized these findings from the task force, along with requirement of effect sizes to publish in their journals. However, Fidler et al. (2005) have conveyed that only slight increases in report rates have been found in popular journals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Statement</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/research-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/research-statement/</guid>
      <description>Upon arriving at Missouri State University, I founded the Deciphering Outrageous Observations and Modeling (DOOM) lab which has included more than ten graduate and thirty undergraduate students. My research mission has been in two primary domains described in detail below and includes many collaborative efforts throughout the years.
Psycholinguistics. My cognitive research focuses broadly on psycholinguistics and memory, particularly on the statistical properties of word relationships. Overall, I seek to understand how language is represented in memory by adding to and examining available linguistic database information (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching Statement</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/teaching-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/teaching-statement/</guid>
      <description>Overview. My approach to teaching centers on the ideas of accessibility, association, and application. As an effective instructor, I strive to ensure that all students are able to orient to and understand material. Often, this process involves formal efforts to reduce barriers to their learning and/or facilitate a stronger grasp of material through association with things they already know. Once students are able to access information, they can begin to understand it and in turn apply it in novel ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/page/basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/page/basics/</guid>
      <description>Basic Information Name: Erin M. Buchanan, Ph.D.
Email: erinbuchanan at missouristate dot edu
Phone: 417-836-5592
Fax: 417-836-8330
Address: Missouri State University
Department of Psychology
901 S. National Ave
Springfield, MO 65897
Education  Ph.D., Experimental Cognitive Psychology, Texas Tech University (2008)  Dissertation: What&amp;rsquo;s the difference: A study on semantic and associative priming and blocking Advisor: Dr. William S. Maki  M.A., Experimental Psychology, Texas Tech University (2006)  Thesis: Feature binding: Not Quite so Pre-Attentive Advisor: Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/page/honors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/page/honors/</guid>
      <description>Honors and Awards  NACADA Academic Advising Excellence Faculty Advisor Award (2016)
 Nominated for the Missouri State Master Online Recognition Award (2016)
 Curtis P. Lawrence Award for Excellence in Advising Recipient, Missouri State University (2016)
 Missouri State University Honors College Curtis P. Lawrence Teaching Award Recipient (2015)
 Missouri State University Honors College Research Award Recipient (2014)
 Nominated for the Missouri State University Foundation Award in Research (2014; 2015)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/page/res_grants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/page/res_grants/</guid>
      <description>Grants Psycholinguistics and memory, general cognitive:  Co-Principal Investigator. To see or not to see: Perceptual learning in organic chemistry. National Science Foundation (2015, submitted). $980,730.00 Principal Investigator. Using Language to Understand Congressional Voting Behaviors. National Science Foundation (2014, submitted). $176,098. Principal Investigator. Studying Semantic Memory of Intelligent Design Systems. IBM&amp;rsquo;s Watson Group. (2014). Applied for access to database. Principal Investigator. Counting tweets: How social media word frequency enhances our understanding of cognition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/page/res_overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/page/res_overview/</guid>
      <description>Research Overview Interests Psycholinguistics and memory: Semantic memory, associative memory, priming of memory types, normed databases, linguistic variables, memory maps, judgments of memory, language statistics, working memory, individual differences.
Statistics: Alternatives to null hypothesis testing, effect sizes and confidence intervals, multigroup confirmatory factor analysis, item response theory, Bayesian inference statistics, hierarchical linear modeling, exploratory factor analysis, statistical reporting
Check out my research statement.
Experience  The DOOM Lab (2010-Current)  Missouri State University, Department of Psychology Principle Investigator</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/page/res_pres/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/page/res_pres/</guid>
      <description>Psycholinguistics and memory, general cognitive:    Download Reference     N/A Maxwell, N. P. &amp;amp; Buchanan, E. M. (2018, April). Single and Double Word-Pair Norms: Predictive Ability of Recall and Judgments. Poster presentation for the Annual Convention of the Midwestern Psychological Association, Chicago, IL.   PDF Maxwell, N. P., Kostic, B., &amp;amp; Buchanan, E.M. (2017, November). The Interaction of Semantic, Thematic, and Associative Overlap Strength in Predicting Recall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/page/res_pubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/page/res_pubs/</guid>
      <description>Publications Psycholinguistics and memory, general cognitive    Download Reference     PDF Scofield, J. E., Buchanan, E. M., &amp;amp; Kostic, B. (in press). A Meta-analysis of the Survival Processing Advantage in Memory, Psychonomic Bulletin &amp;amp; Review, doi:10.3758/s13423-017-1346-0   PDF Marshall, C.Z.* &amp;amp; Buchanan, E.M. (2016). The effect of personal distance on the perception of LGBTQ+ hate speech. LOGOS: A Journal of Undergraduate Research, 9, 30-43.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/page/service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/page/service/</guid>
      <description>Professional Memberships  Midwestern Psychological Association Southwestern Psychological Association Psychonomic Society Association for Psychological Science Graduate and Professional Student Association  University Service  GradCAS &amp;ldquo;Dream Team&amp;rdquo; (Graduate Application Redesign, 2018-Current) Statistics Couse Redesign, Chair (2018-Current) Application System Coordinator (2014-Current) Departmental Assessment Committee (2014-Current) Graduate Council (2013-2017) Comprehensive Exam Coordinator (2013-Current) Coordinator of Statistics Help Lab (2013-Current) Graduate Review Committee (2013-Current) Reviewer for Journal of Clinical Psychology (2013-Current) Multidisciplinary Forum (2012-2014) Departmental Search Committees (2012-Current) Reviewer for Behavior Research Methods (2012-Current) Pre-Law Advisor (2012-Current) Honors College Advisor (2011-Current) Living Learning Community Faculty Advisor (2011-2012) Space Utilization Committee, Chair, (2011-Current) CHHS Assessment Committee (2011-Current) PASS Faculty Fellow (2011-Current) Course Evaluation Redesign and Coordinator (2011-Current) RStats Consultant (2011-Current) Recruitment Committee, Chair, (2011-Current) Major&amp;rsquo;s Fair (2010-Current) Bear Claw Advisory Board (2010-Current) Research Writing Group (2010-Current) Editorial Board for Journal of Scientific Psychology (2009-Current) Honors Thesis Supervisor (2009-Current) Psychonomic Society Member (2008-Current) Master&amp;rsquo;s Thesis Committees (2008-Current) Honors Thesis Committees (2009-Current) Reviewer for the Journal of Scientific Psychology (2007 - Current) Faculty Supervisor for Photography Club (2008 - 2010) Vice President of the Student Experimental Counsel (2007-2008) Psychology Textbook Adoption Committee (2006) Treasurer of the Student Experimental Counsel (2005-2006)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/page/stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/page/stats/</guid>
      <description>Here, you can learn about our goal of making statistical analysis approachable by creating a plethora of learning materials and interactive environment for learning/improving your skills.
Shiny Apps: I have been working on building interactive applications through Shiny to visualize the data for specific projects and to increase statistical skills by creating easy ways to calculate numbers for non-programming researchers. I try to post about the applications as we put them online, but you can find them on our shiny-server GitHub repository or through the shiny tag on the blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/page/students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/page/students/</guid>
      <description>Graduate Students DOOM Lab Students    School, Year Name Thesis     MSU, 2017-2019 Addie Wikowsky TBD   MSU, 2017-2019 William Padfield TBD   MSU, 2016-2018 David Herr Generativity and Trauma in first responders   MSU, 2016-2018 Nick Maxwell Models of memory and judgment   MSU, 2015-2017 Katherine Miller The Mediating Effects of Cortisol on Memory and Judgments of Learning   MSU, 2015-2017 Rebecca Knoph Language Learning and Metacognition: An Interventions to Improve Language Classrooms   MSU, 2014-2016 Jahnavi Delmonico Politics, Personality, and Sensitivity to Change   MSU, 2013-2015 Marshall Beauchamp IRT Analyses of Body Dissatisfaction in Men   MSU, 2013-2015 Kayla Jordan Linguistic Markers of Writing about War   MSU, 2012-2014 Marilee Teasley When Music Goes Up in Flames: The Impact of Academic Advising on the Perceived Burnout of Music Majors   MSU, 2011-2013 Kathrene Valentine Alternatives: A Comparison of Parametric, Nonparametric, and Observation Oriented Modeling techniques    Master&amp;rsquo;s Theses Supervised    School, Year Name Thesis     MSU, 2018 Heather Lepper TBD   MSU, 2018 Emily Klug TBD   MSU, 2018 Kirby Williams TBD   MSU, 2017 Michael Mizer Assessment of Reliability and Stability of Various Visual Search Parameters   MSU, 2017 Rachel Swadley Returning to abusive relationships: Related and predictive factors   MSU, 2017 Jordan Henslee Body image and bodybuilding: the impact commitment to bodybuilding has on body image disturband among competitive bodybuilders   MSU, 2017 John Scofield Desirability Heuristics: A replication and extension of Hill and Bus (2008) experiment 1   MSU, 2017 Jessica Willis The effects of motivation and goal setting on response latency and mental effort   MSU, 2017 Shannon Hayden Contemplative practices and test anxiety   MSU, 2016 Jamie Smith Evaluating the effectiveness of an ecological intervention targeting body checking behaviors   MSU, 2016 Samantha Hunter Message framing and source factors: Peers&amp;rsquo; impact on exercise intentions   MSU, 2016 Benjamin Graves Methods of measuring visual scanning of puright and inverted ecological measures   MSU, 2016 Amy Bauman Exploration of factors in established scales regarding attitudes toward sex offenders   MSU, 2016 Elizabeth Gelhaus Student athletes and factors that determine their social support circle   MSU, 2015 My Vu Climbing the taxonomy ladder with help from the keyword method   MSU, 2015 Kristyn Angsten Evaluating severity differences of depression and anxiety in self- report and clinician-rated measures   MSU, 2015 Brooke Bennett Examination of the effects of media consumption on mood and body dissatisfaction using ecological momentary assessment   MSU, 2015 Vanessa Jones Barriers to Mental Healthcare across age groups   MSU, 2015 Alexandra Jauregui-Dusseau Differences in Pain Resolution post-ACLR Comparing Patellar Tendon and Hamstring Autografts   MSU, 2015 Amy Smith Knowledge and attitudes of certified athletic trainers toward providing care for athletes with cerebral palsy   MSU, 2015 Jillian Burroughs Reliability testing for the interprofessional collaborative practice assessment for athletic training   MSU, 2014 Carrie Melia Scanning Patterns and the Role of Recognition Memory for Novel and Primed Faces   MSU, 2014 Emily Stefano Examination of the Effects of Repeated Body Checking on Body Image Dissatisfaction and Negative Affect Using Ecological Momentary   MSU, 2014 Cory Derringer Adaptive Memory: Is Recall Affected by Sex-Specific Jealousy Cues?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/page/teach_overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/page/teach_overview/</guid>
      <description> Teaching Overview Interests Read my teaching statement.
Undergraduate:
 Cognition Statistics Research Methods/Experimental Design  Graduate:
 Experimental Methods Basic Statistics (ANOVA, Regression) Advanced Statistics (Multivariate, Structural Equation Modeling) Nonparametric Statistics Cognition, Attention, Memory, Language  Courses Taught Undergraduate:
 Cognitive Psychology General Psychology Lab in Cognitive Psychology Statistics for Social Sciences Advanced Statistics Research Methods Psycholinguistics Freshman Honor&amp;rsquo;s Seminar  Graduate:
 Regression/Factor Analysis Multivariate Statistics Advanced Statistics Graduate Statistics Structural Equation Modeling Bayesian Methods Nonparametrics  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Erin</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Professionally Speaking I am currently an Associate Professor of Psychology at Missouri State University. MSU is the second largest 4 year public university with approximately 25,000 students in Missouri. The Psychology department is fairly large - with nearly 1,000 undergraduate majors (including a double major in gerontology), 30ish full time faculty, and 50-60 graduate students in one of our three tracks (experimental, I/O, clinical). I work closely with the Experimental Psychology track in our master&amp;rsquo;s program and direct the Statistics and Research Design graduate certificate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/page/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/page/cv/</guid>
      <description>My name is Inigo Montoya. I have the following qualities:
 I rock a great mustache I&amp;rsquo;m extremely loyal to my family  What else do you need?
my history To be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m having some trouble remembering right now, so why don&amp;rsquo;t you just watch my movie and it will answer all your questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/page/lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/page/lab/</guid>
      <description>My name is Inigo Montoya. I have the following qualities:
 I rock a great mustache I&amp;rsquo;m extremely loyal to my family  What else do you need?
my history To be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m having some trouble remembering right now, so why don&amp;rsquo;t you just watch my movie and it will answer all your questions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>