<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>formr on Dr. Erin Buchanan</title>
    <link>https://doomlab.github.io/tags/formr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in formr on Dr. Erin Buchanan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://doomlab.github.io/tags/formr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>formr Round 4</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/formr-round-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/formr-round-4/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s be four years since the last formr update! Good grief. I am building a new server for PSA research projects, so I thought I would share the latest updates and installs for those who want it for their own use. I will also note that the formr dudes recommend docker installation as shown here: https://github.com/rubenarslan/formr_dev_docker. My luck with docker is so-so, so here&amp;rsquo;s my guide for manual install. Further, their warning about &amp;ldquo;no production&amp;rdquo; makes me quite nervous.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>formr Round 3: No nginx Required</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/formr-round-3-no-nginx-required/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/formr-round-3-no-nginx-required/</guid>
      <description>Alright folks! I am back with more installation guides. I&amp;rsquo;ve installed formr so many times at this point &amp;hellip; since my first post, opencpu has updated to R 4+, and I&amp;rsquo;ve found a way to not use nginx. Which is good news, since it often conflicts with also running apache. I&amp;rsquo;m going to leave the old guides up because maybe they can help someone figure out their issues, but here goes with the newest guide.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>formr Installation Instructions</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/formr-installation-instructions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/formr-installation-instructions/</guid>
      <description>An installation guide taken from formr documentation and modified to include more details for those who need it.
These installation instructions are provided for Ubuntu 18.04; however, they could be modified for other systems. The original instructions suggest Debian 9, but I found this much easier on Ubuntu. I have now used both Digital Ocean and Amazon Lightsail for this installation. I don’t think the product matters, but the size of the machine is likely something you should focus on.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
