<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>how-to on Dr. Erin Buchanan</title>
    <link>/tags/how-to/</link>
    <description>Recent content in how-to on Dr. Erin Buchanan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/how-to/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing RStudio Server &#43; Updates</title>
      <link>/post/installing-rstudio-server-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>/post/installing-rstudio-server-updates/</guid>
      <description>One of the most difficult things I try to teach my students is how to deal with error messages. Due to Hurricane Laura, I am currently re-creating several projects including formr, RStudio, and a website. I thought I would detail that here.
You can find my first post on formr here: https://www.aggieerin.com/post/formr-installation-instructions/
Good news! It’s mostly the same and pretty smooth. However, I sometimes get this nonsense: installation of package ‘psych’ had non-zero exit status - any time you get the non-zero exit status message, it requires a careful look at the installation messages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>formr Installation Instructions</title>
      <link>/post/formr-installation-instructions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>/post/formr-installation-instructions/</guid>
      <description>An installation guide taken from formr documentation and modified to include more details for those who need it.
These installation instructions are provided for Ubuntu 18.04; however, they could be modified for other systems. The original instructions suggest Debian 9, but I found this much easier on Ubuntu. I have now used both Digital Ocean and Amazon Lightsail for this installation. I don’t think the product matters, but the size of the machine is likely something you should focus on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lasso Myself Numbers</title>
      <link>/post/lasso-myself-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>/post/lasso-myself-numbers/</guid>
      <description>Hey everybody!
The last couple days I have been trying to learn LASSO regression, which stands for Least Absolute Shrinkage and Selection Operator. I have several datasets with many variables, and I thought these would be a good opportunity to learn about how to lasso, while maybe answering a few questions about words.
Right, the part I forgot about is that I have repeated measures data, which always complicates things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Translations with rvest and Selenium</title>
      <link>/post/getting-translations-with-rvest-and-selenium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>/post/getting-translations-with-rvest-and-selenium/</guid>
      <description>In this guide, I’ll go over how you can use web scraping rvest and Selenium to get translations from Google Translate. Note: I encourage responsible scraping - I always try to do it with some space between requests. You can only do 5000 characters at a time with the free Google translate. I will say that I tried to do this with just rvest and the predictability of the links for Google translate - but I could not get rvest to pull the right data off the page, so here’s a slightly more difficult approach that appears to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating Your CV with Packages</title>
      <link>/post/updating-your-cv-with-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>/post/updating-your-cv-with-packages/</guid>
      <description>Hi guys! I have finally done it! I updated my CV with Rmarkdown using Steve&amp;rsquo;s Markdown Templates. I was tempted to use the new vitae package, but I had already gone down this path before that came out, just finally getting back to it.
Link to the entire CV folder for you to use/view do stuff with: CV. Please ignore the html files in that folder, it does &amp;ldquo;knit&amp;rdquo; automatically as part of the website build using markdown - you should be using PDF and LaTex for the CV part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JASP Videos &#43; Guides</title>
      <link>/post/jasp-videos-guides/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>/post/jasp-videos-guides/</guid>
      <description>Hey everybody! I am back and finally getting to videos again. I hesistate to say “it’s been crazy!” because I feel like that’s always a thing that academics say, but I will say I’ve had a lot of life going on, and I am finally getting back to a normal amount of crazy.
I’ve decided to do some simple videos to start - so I am creating how-to videos to go with our JASP guides we created this summer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>