<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publication on Dr. Erin Buchanan</title>
    <link>https://doomlab.github.io/tags/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publication on Dr. Erin Buchanan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://doomlab.github.io/tags/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New Publications and Updated CV</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/new-publications-and-updated-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/new-publications-and-updated-cv/</guid>
      <description>Hi guys! I just wanted to post that I&amp;rsquo;ve updated the website to be current with some new publications I wanted to highlight:
First up is two papers on psycholinguistics that were undergraduate student projects:
Duncan, J., Buchanan, E.M., Marshall, C.Z., &amp;amp; Oberdieck, K. (accepted). But words will never hurt me, Journal of Psychology and Behavioral Sciences, X, XX-XX. PDF
Forbes, F.-J., &amp;amp; Buchanan, E. M. (accepted). “Textisms”: The Comfort of the Recipient, Psychology of Popular Media Culture, X, XX-XX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Current Publications with Papaja</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/current-publications-with-papaja/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/current-publications-with-papaja/</guid>
      <description>Heyo! Frederik, the author of papaja, requested that we update him with papers written with his package. I was like, oh man, like the whole lab?! So, I decided that I could probably make it easy by making a table here. Obviously, this table is current at the moment, as I hope many of the ones under review will get accepted, and I have several others that we will start writing soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Publication: Texting</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/new-publication-texting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/new-publication-texting/</guid>
      <description>One more announcement! We just had a new publication accepted:
&amp;ldquo;Textisms&amp;rdquo;: The Comfort of the Recipient: This paper was an undergraduate honors thesis that Flora-Jean and I finally got accepted! She did a great job making sure this paper was completed and published.
You can check out the materials here: https://osf.io/8kt52/
You can view the pre-print: https://osf.io/ptf7c/
We should have the real print up soon! Just waiting on the journal now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Publications</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/new-publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/new-publications/</guid>
      <description>Just wanted to do a quick post to say that the Nature Human Behavior response paper, Justify Your Alpha is now online at NHB&amp;rsquo;s website: Springer - it is free to view but not download. You can download the PDF version on OSF.
We&amp;rsquo;ve submitted a couple new papers as well - updated those on my research publications page. I also have a couple more to get done - hoping to feature some of the cool coding work I&amp;rsquo;ve done this week after taking a breather from a seriously packed week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Publication - Detect Low Quality Data</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/new-publication-detect-low-quality-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/new-publication-detect-low-quality-data/</guid>
      <description>My coauthor John Scofield and I just had a publication accepted at Behavior Research Methods - you can check out the publication preprint at OSF.
We thew together a website for the paper that summarizes everything we found, as well as puts all the materials together in one place - check it out.
We create a really nice R function to help you detect low quality data, which you can find on GitHub, and I even made a video that explains all the parts to the function at YouTube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citations in R Markdown &#43; Papaja</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/citations-in-r-markdown-papaja/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/citations-in-r-markdown-papaja/</guid>
      <description>Heyo! I wanted to write a post about some of the quirky things I&amp;rsquo;ve found with writing manuscripts in R Markdown, as well as provide a solution to a problem that someone else might be having.
Update: The csl file I describe below is a special formatted one, which was shared with me. You can download it from GitHub to try the suggestions below.
Update 2: Turns out, potentially, the suggestions from the manual are not working correctly, as Frederik has checked it out and opened an issue on github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Shiny App to Compare Stats</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/a-shiny-app-to-compare-stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/a-shiny-app-to-compare-stats/</guid>
      <description>For a recent publication comparing null hypothesis testing p-values to Bayes Factors and Observation Oriented Modeling, we created a Shiny app to graph all of our complex plots. I particularly pleased with the plotly 3D graph - as I usually think that 3D graphs are impossible to read. This plot shows what we found in our study (albeit I would recommend viewing the 2D plots more):
 Bayes Factors and p-values follow a power function, as we expected.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>