<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Dr. Erin Buchanan</title>
    <link>https://doomlab.github.io/categories/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Dr. Erin Buchanan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://doomlab.github.io/categories/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New Publication - Detect Low Quality Data</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/new-publication-detect-low-quality-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/new-publication-detect-low-quality-data/</guid>
      <description>My coauthor John Scofield and I just had a publication accepted at Behavior Research Methods - you can check out the publication preprint at OSF.
We thew together a website for the paper that summarizes everything we found, as well as puts all the materials together in one place - check it out.
We create a really nice R function to help you detect low quality data, which you can find on GitHub, and I even made a video that explains all the parts to the function at YouTube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citations in R Markdown &#43; Papaja</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/citations-in-r-markdown-papaja/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/citations-in-r-markdown-papaja/</guid>
      <description>Heyo! I wanted to write a post about some of the quirky things I&amp;rsquo;ve found with writing manuscripts in R Markdown, as well as provide a solution to a problem that someone else might be having.
Update: The csl file I describe below is a special formatted one, which was shared with me. You can download it from GitHub to try the suggestions below.
Update 2: Turns out, potentially, the suggestions from the manual are not working correctly, as Frederik has checked it out and opened an issue on github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Shiny App to Compare Stats</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/a-shiny-app-to-compare-stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/a-shiny-app-to-compare-stats/</guid>
      <description>For a recent publication comparing null hypothesis testing p-values to Bayes Factors and Observation Oriented Modeling, we created a Shiny app to graph all of our complex plots. I particularly pleased with the plotly 3D graph - as I usually think that 3D graphs are impossible to read. This plot shows what we found in our study (albeit I would recommend viewing the 2D plots more):
 Bayes Factors and p-values follow a power function, as we expected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn About MOTE</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/learn-about-mote/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/learn-about-mote/</guid>
      <description>The APA Task Force on Statistical Inference (Wilkinson &amp;amp; TFSI, 1999) has advocated the inclusion of effect sizes in journal articles as an important source of information. The fifth and current edition of the APA publication manual (2001, 2010) emphasized these findings from the task force, along with requirement of effect sizes to publish in their journals. However, Fidler et al. (2005) have conveyed that only slight increases in report rates have been found in popular journals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Statement</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/research-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/research-statement/</guid>
      <description>Upon arriving at Missouri State University, I founded the Deciphering Outrageous Observations and Modeling (DOOM) lab which has included more than ten graduate and thirty undergraduate students. My research mission has been in two primary domains described in detail below and includes many collaborative efforts throughout the years.
Psycholinguistics. My cognitive research focuses broadly on psycholinguistics and memory, particularly on the statistical properties of word relationships. Overall, I seek to understand how language is represented in memory by adding to and examining available linguistic database information (i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>