<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>statistics on Dr. Erin Buchanan</title>
    <link>https://doomlab.github.io/tags/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in statistics on Dr. Erin Buchanan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://doomlab.github.io/tags/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Multilevel Modeling Workshop Materials</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/multilevel-modeling-workshop-materials/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/multilevel-modeling-workshop-materials/</guid>
      <description>Many thanks to Rutgers University Spanish and Portuguese Department (https://span-port.rutgers.edu/) for asking me to come talk about multilevel models. I enjoyed talking to the group, meeting Twitter friends in real life!, and I am especially impressed by what their department is doing in what is often considered a qualitative science.
I used RStudio&amp;rsquo;s Cloud to share a workspace with all the materials, packages, and other information you might need. I built the slide show using markdown, so that people could watch the slides and/or take their own notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JASP Videos &#43; Guides</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/jasp-videos-guides/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/jasp-videos-guides/</guid>
      <description>Hey everybody! I am back and finally getting to videos again. I hesistate to say “it’s been crazy!” because I feel like that’s always a thing that academics say, but I will say I’ve had a lot of life going on, and I am finally getting back to a normal amount of crazy.
I’ve decided to do some simple videos to start - so I am creating how-to videos to go with our JASP guides we created this summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick and Dirty Categorical lavaan</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/quick-and-dirty-categorical-lavaan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/quick-and-dirty-categorical-lavaan/</guid>
      <description>I was tagged today on twitter asking about categorical variables in lavaan. I will say I have not done much with categorical predictors either endogenous or exogenous. I did a quick reproducible example of exogenous variables, and I will refer you to the help guide for lavaan here.
You will need both the lavaan and psych packages to reproduce this code. Ironically, this data is binary outcome data (the epi dataset in psych), which wasn&amp;rsquo;t intentional, I just knew it was a good dataset to work with to test how to do exogenous categorical variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Publications and Updated CV</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/new-publications-and-updated-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/new-publications-and-updated-cv/</guid>
      <description>Hi guys! I just wanted to post that I&amp;rsquo;ve updated the website to be current with some new publications I wanted to highlight:
First up is two papers on psycholinguistics that were undergraduate student projects:
Duncan, J., Buchanan, E.M., Marshall, C.Z., &amp;amp; Oberdieck, K. (accepted). But words will never hurt me, Journal of Psychology and Behavioral Sciences, X, XX-XX. PDF
Forbes, F.-J., &amp;amp; Buchanan, E. M. (accepted). “Textisms”: The Comfort of the Recipient, Psychology of Popular Media Culture, X, XX-XX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mediation Moderation Workshop</title>
      <link>https://doomlab.github.io/post/mediation-moderation-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (aggieerin.com)</author>
      <guid>https://doomlab.github.io/post/mediation-moderation-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone!
I have been super swamped with a bunch of due dates that all hit in April. For a small brag, and I like making lists:
9 revise and resubmits (four we&amp;rsquo;ve sent back, two have been accepted!) 4 conference posters and one invited talk 1 submitted grant (fingers crossed!) 2 invited papers 2 theses that I&amp;rsquo;m chairing, 2 that I&amp;rsquo;m on the committee for Data camp! It&amp;rsquo;s been nuts, so haven&amp;rsquo;t left the house much or done much of anything else.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
